The true untold story.
Chevalier is a music, drama, history film directed by Stephen Williams.
The illegitimate son of an African slave and a French plantation owner, Joseph Bologne rises to improbable heights in French society as a
celebrated violinist-composer and fencer, complete with an ill-fated love affair and a falling out with Marie Antoinette and her court.
Joseph, played by Kelvin Harrison, Jr..
Marie-Josephine, played by Samara Weaving.
Marie Antoinette, played by Lucy Boynton.
Philippe, played by Alex Fitzalan.
La Guimard, played by Minnie Driver.
Madame de Genlis, played by Sian Clifford.
Chevalier is a 2022 American biographical drama film based on the life of the French-Caribbean
musician Joseph Bologne, Chevalier de Saint-Georges, played by Kelvin Harrison Jr.
Directed by Stephen Williams and written by Stefani Robinson, it stars Samara Weaving, Lucy
Boynton, Marton Csokas, Alex Fitzalan, Minnie Driver and Ronkẹ Adékoluẹjo.
Chevalier had its world premiere at the 47th Toronto International Film Festival on September 11,
2022, and was released in the United States by Searchlight Pictures on April 21, 2023.
The film received generally favorable reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of biography, marie antoinette,
based on true story, violinist, 18th century.
The tone is emotional.